<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://www.careys.space/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://www.careys.space/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-10T21:35:49-05:00</updated><id>http://www.careys.space/</id><title type="html">Carey’s Space</title><subtitle>This is just my attempt to fill time for now. Perhaps it will be something else later.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Computering is hard</title><link href="http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/10/computering-is-hard.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Computering is hard" /><published>2018-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/10/computering-is-hard</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/10/computering-is-hard.html">&lt;p&gt;So, I decided that I wanted a really inexpensive way to host this blog. Github seemed to be the least hassle, since I’d already set up github pages a couple years ago and then forgot about it. Mind you, I’m a little rusty at all this. It’s been the better part of a decade since I’ve managed a domain or done any code troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namecheap (my domain registrar) has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecheap.com/support/knowledgebase/article.aspx/9645/2208/how-do-i-link-my-domain-to-github-pages&quot;&gt;step-by-step tutorial&lt;/a&gt; on setting your domain to point to gh. Now, gh uses Jekyll to serve up web pages, so I dl’ed that and put up my test page on localhost. Looked good. Using markdown was &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; easier than hand-coding HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, how do I publish this? There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://ixti.net/software/2013/01/28/using-jekyll-plugins-on-github-pages.html&quot;&gt;very helpful tutorial&lt;/a&gt; out there on using rake to compile your jekyll files and automagically put them up on github, but it literally took me &lt;em&gt;hours&lt;/em&gt; to get it to work. I was missing one command line argument. I’m not even entirely sure how I noticed it, but once I fixed it… &lt;strong&gt;wham!&lt;/strong&gt; It’s like the heavens parted and dropped my completed site right onto github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except now gh is saying that my domain doesn’t point to a gh-pages repository. Now what?! I poke thru settings, the regular &lt;em&gt;username&lt;/em&gt;.github.io address works, but github thinks careys.space is no longer pointing to a gh-pages site. I troll thru the Namecheap tutorial. Of course! The gh-pages site needs a CNAME file to serve up the repository as a domain. Of course, this file didn’t exist locally and got nuked when I committed the website on git. Fortunately, that only took me a few minutes (okay, 20 minutes) to figure out. There’s nothing quite like the satisfaction you feel when you’re working your way through errors and technical roadblocks to finally achieve your goals, but man, computering is hard sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">So, I decided that I wanted a really inexpensive way to host this blog. Github seemed to be the least hassle, since I’d already set up github pages a couple years ago and then forgot about it. Mind you, I’m a little rusty at all this. It’s been the better part of a decade since I’ve managed a domain or done any code troubleshooting.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I was bored so I did a Thing</title><link href="http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/09/i-was-bored-so-i-did-a-thing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I was bored so I did a Thing" /><published>2018-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/09/i-was-bored-so-i-did-a-thing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://www.careys.space/blog/update/2018/03/09/i-was-bored-so-i-did-a-thing.html">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the world of medical recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only an hour or so under the knife, and it takes weeks to recover. That’s where I’m at. Since I’m in no condition to - say - work with power tools, I decided to start fiddling with websites and whatnot. You know, low impact hobby-type stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I discovered that I had an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/careman71/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; account that I didn’t know I had. So I posted a couple photos there. But honestly, I’m also not in a position to walk around and take photos, and there’s only so many pictures I can take of my bullet journal or bed clothes. So, why not see what I can get up to on the Interwebs?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve decided to create this place &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.careys.space&quot;&gt;careys.space&lt;/a&gt; and learn some new stuff (specifically, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll static page editor&lt;/a&gt; hosted at github… for &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;. I know: the &lt;strong&gt;.space&lt;/strong&gt; domain is supposed to be for stuff related to, well, space and astronomy and whatnot. But it’s also nice to have your own &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt;, right? Plus, it was literally only $.86 to register (that includes the ICANN fee). Thanks NameCheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a nice challenge to exercise the old brain muscles after weeks of consuming YouTube pap. Idk if blogging is really my thing, but watch this space if you care. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Welcome to the world of medical recovery.</summary></entry></feed>